All of my friends.
We are going to solve exercise number 22, and in this exercise, we are asking to see how the factorial
method and the recursion works.
So we are going to analyze this function and drew out a conclusion how the recursion works.
So we need to make a step by step and solve step by step.
This method both the video and think about it.
Please write that your answer in your own paper and comment your solution in the comments below.
In order to make ad like discussions and solve any problem you are facing.
So how to solve like these questions we have here in the main main method and we start in the Java and
main method, and we see that system without the print factor of five is factorial five.
OK.
This function, factorial five is here and we are passing, calling this function and passing number
five.
Inside it as a perimeter and now an equal to five, acting as a perimeter and inside it, if an equal
equal to one return and one else retired and times factorial of n minus one.
OK, so let's go and.
Make the hear how they're at this function works.
OK, so we said that we are calling the method factorial of five.
OK.
OK, guys, this is factorial of five five is passed here.
A returning if we see here.
That there is.
Check if an equal equal to one.
No.
And equal to five now, it was returned, and time is factorial of and times minus one.
OK, so.
This factor of five is equal to.
This factorial is equal to five.
This is an.
Times factorial of and minus one, which is thought.
OK, so this is end, and this is times factorial of and minus one.
OK.
Now.
Factorial of four is here.
OK.
We need to get factor of four, so factorial offshore in the same way is equal to four times factorial
of and minus one, but now becomes four.
So factorial.
Of the city.
OK, now factorial of three.
Is equal to three times factorial of two.
OK, now factorial of two.
You see, guys, how the recursion works it up in the space.
It stopped here five times factorial of four.
So the rest of the program is not going to be executed unless this would be finished, and this is one
of the problems of using recursion.
So factor four, go and make this sequence OK.
Factorial of two equals two times factorial of one.
And factorial of one, we know that if an equal equal to one.
This is one one in return, one.
OK, so this is the first item we are going to be calculating, calculating.
OK, so this one?
Is a return to here and being replaced?
OK, guys.
How that occasion works, it uses and the stopped at a limit, so it uses a limit factorial of what
its users want and equal to one to be limited, always use limiting behavior and limiting factor, limiting
factor and limiting and limiting variable or algorithm in order to stop recursion.
Or you are going to be entering an infinite recursion and you this will lead into a mess in the memory.
So one is being replaced here and a return and being substituted by this function factorial of one.
So two times one is equal to two.
OK, now this is that answer of factorial of 2.0.
Factorial of two is equal to two.
Now two is being replaced here because this is the factor of two.
You see, guys, how that the method, how the the algorithm of recursion works, OK.
And the behavior of recursion works.
So two is being replaced by factorial of two.
Three times two is six.
So six is the.
Answer of factorial of three.
OK.
Now six is going to be replacing the factorial of three function here.
So four times six is equal to twenty four.
OK.
You see, guys, this is how recursion works.
And 24, it is their factorial of four.
So factor to look for this function when being replaced whenever seen by 24.
So going up.
To our the main method.
Five times factorial of four.
We are replacing this by 24.
This will give us five times.
Sorry for at this writing five times.
24.
Five times twenty four is equal to one.
20.
This is the factorial of five.
In this way, we are calculating and behaving and the Haricharan ambiguity during.